Guide to the World Student Christian Federation Africa Region Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
World Student Christian Federation Africa Region Records
1971-2012
RG 46D
Yale University Divinity School Library
2.5
(6 boxes)
The archives of the World Student Christian Federation Africa Regional Office include legal documents, minutes, financial records, and documentation of workshops and consultations dealing with issues such as human rights, women's leadership, conflict transformation, HIV and AIDS, and economic justice.
World Student Christian Federation. Africa Office
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Deposited by the World Student Christian Federation Africa Regional Office, 2007, 2012
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
WSCF was founded in 1895 with the aim of uniting movements or associations of Christian students throughout the world. The Federation is organized into six regions, each with its own regional office. The regions and the locations of their regional offices are as follows: Africa (Nairobi) Asia Pacific (Hong Kong) Europe (Budapest) Latin America and the Caribbean (Buenos Aires) Middle East (Lebanon) North America and Canada (New York).
The Africa Regional Office is located in Nairobi, Kenya and coordinates the efforts of 24 national movements across the continent. These national movements are called student Christian movements or SCMs. In addition to the SCMs, there are also several associate groups and organizations affiliated with the Federation through the Africa Regional Office. The organizational structure of the WSCF Africa Region includes the Africa Regional Committee (ARC), the Regional Executive Committee, and Sub-regional Committees.
Scope and Contents
These are the official archives of the World Student Christian Federation Africa Regional Office. Many of the documents are available in both English and French. Series I contains legal documents. Series II contains minutes of the Africa Consultative Group, Africa Region Executive Committee, and Africa Regional Committee. Series III contains documentation of training programs and consultations sponsored by the Africa Region from 1987 to 2006, including on on human rights, women's leadership, conflict transformation, HIV and AIDS, and economic justice. Series IV contains financial statements dating from 1986-2006. Series V, Addendum 2013, includes material similar to what is contained in the earlier series, dating from 2008 to 2012.
Arrangement
I. Legal Documents, 1979-2003
II. Governing Bodies, 1971-2006
III. Program Documentation, 1987-2006
IV. Financial Records, 1986-2006
V. Addendum 2013
Youth in the ecumenical movement -- Africa; Church and social problems -- Africa; World Student Christian Federation. Africa Office
- Legal Documents, 1979-2003; Series I
  - Africa Region By-Laws and Constitution (English and French), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Income Tax Department Personal Identification Number Certificate, Certificate of Registration as Non-Governmental Organization (photocopies), 1995, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lease agreements for premises in "Church House" of National Council of Churches of Kenya, 1981, 1989, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Governing Bodies, 1971-; Series II
  - Africa Consultative Group
    - Minutes of meetings in Nairobi, Addis Ababa, Ibadan, Yaounde, Lusaka, 1971, 1972, 1973, 1974, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Africa Regional Committee (ARC)
    - Bound volume of minutes of meetings in Mombasa, Nairobi, Limuru, Yamoussoukro, Yaounde, 1977, 1979, 1983, 1986, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Program for meeting in Harare, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Minutes of meeting in Bajumbura, Burundi, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Report of WSCF Africa Regional Committee meeting and Leadership Development Programme, Addis Ababa, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Minutes of meeting in Yamoussoukro, Ivory Coast, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Study book and minutes of meeting in Nairobi, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Minutes of meeting in Accra, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Program and minutes of meeting in Nairobi, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Minutes of meeting in Dar Es Salaam, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Africa Region Executive Committee
    - Minutes, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Report of Extended Executive Committe meeting in Maseru, Lesotho, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Minutes of meetings in Yaounde, Ibadan, Nairobi, Ivory Coast, 1980, 1982, 1983-1984, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Minutes of meetings in Nairobi, and Kigali, Rwanda, 1991, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Minutes of meetings held in Johannesburg and Nairobi, 1994, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Minutes of meetings held in Nairobi and Legon, Ghana, 1996, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Minutes of meetings held in Yaounde and Kpalime, Togo, 1999, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Minutes of meetings held in Machakos and Nairobi, Kenya and Dar Es Salaam, 2003, 2005, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Program Documentation, 1987-2006; Series III
  - International Student Round-Table on Disarmament and Development, Harare, Zimbabwe, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Women Commission Workshop, Bakau, The Gambia, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Consultations on Human Rights Education, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Female Students' Commission meetings, Accra, Ghana, 1999, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Leadership and Capacity Building Workshop, Kampala, Uganda, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Africa 2000 Forum: ICA and African Partners Meeting, Mbagathi, Kenya (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Conflict transformation and Capacity Building Workshop, Sudan, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Young Women's Continental Planning Consultation, Nairobi, Kenya, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Response to HIV and AIDS Among Youth and Students - Trainers workshop, Bulawayo, Zimbabwe and Accra, Ghana, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Peace Building and Conflict Transformation - Trainers workshop, Nairobi, Kenya, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - YouthNet's Regional Faith-Based Initiative: Sexuality, Reproductive Health and HIV/AIDS Prevention: Planning Meeting, Nairobi, Kenya, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Formation des Formateurs en Construction di la Paix et la Résolution des Conflicts Pour la Région de l'Afrique Centrale, Bujumbura, Burundi, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Ecumenical Leadership Training, Limuru, Kenya, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - "Christian and Muslim Leaders Combating AIDS": A Training in Adolescent Sexuality, Reproductive Health and HIV/AIDS, Johannesburg, South Africa, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Peace Building and Conflict Transformation - Trainers workshops, Kampala, Uganda and Nairobi, Kenya, 2004, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Female Student Commission Workshops, Accra, Ghana and Nairobi, Kenya, 2004, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Training on Economic Justice, Nairobi, Kenya, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Leadership formation workshops, Bujumbara, Burundi and Antananarivo, Madagascar, 2005, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - HIV/AIDS / Economic Justice workshops, Lesotho and Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Financial Records, 1986-2006; Series IV
  - Audited financial statements, 1986-1990 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Audit reports and audited financial statements, 1991, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Audited financial statements, 1993-1998 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Audited financial statements, 2001-2006 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Addendum, 2013, 2007-2012; Series V
  - Administrative Records
    - Legal records
      - By-laws (new regional by-laws), 2012 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Lease agreements, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Staff records
      - Staff CVs and contracts, 2009-2011 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Personnel Policy manual, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Board and Committee Records
      - Africa Regional Committee meeting, Nairobi, 2008 Jul (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Africa Executive Committee meetings (Nairobi 2008, 2010; Burundi 2012), 2008 Apr, 2010 Aug, 2012 Jul (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Senior Friends meeting, Nairobi, 2011 Aug (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Program Documentation
    - Annual programs
      - Activities and budget, 2008, 2009, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Activities and budget, 2011, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Strategic planning
      - Strategic priorities 2009-2012 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Training reports
      - Human Rights Training - Nairobi, Kenya, 2008 Jul (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Seminaire de Formation des Jeune Leaders en Justice Economique et VIH/SIDA - Kigali, Rwanda, 2008 Oct (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Sub-Regional Training of Youth Leader in Economic Justice - Lusaka, Zambia, 2008 Nov-Dec (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Seminaire de Formation des Leaders sur la Securite Alimentaire - Yaounde, Cameroun, 2009 May-Jun (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - East Africa Sub-Regional Training on HIV and AIDS Link to Economic Justice - Kampala, Uganda, 2009 Aug (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Sous-Region Afrique De L'Ouest et Afrique Centrale, Seminaire de Formation des Leaders sur lat Justice Climatique - Porto Novo, Benin, 2010 Sep (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Training on Gender and Human Rights - Kigali, Rwanda and Windhoek, Namibia, 2010 Dec, 2011 Apr (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Seminaire National, Renforcement des Capcities dur le Genre et les Droits de la Personne - Kinshas, Congo, 2011 Jul (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Formation Sous Regionale sur la Prevention et la Lutte contre la Corruption - Bagbe, Togo, 2011 Oct (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - National Workshop on Peace Building in Sierra Leone, 2011 Oct (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Sub-Regional Training, WSCF Action on Migration and Sub-Regional Training, WSCF Africa Action on Climate Change - Arusha, Tanzania, 2011 Nov (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Financial Records
    - Annual audited accounts, 2008-2011 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Reports and Publications
    - Activities reports, 2008-2001 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Printouts of E-Newsletters, 2009-2011 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Book: "A Historical Journey of Service and Faithful Witness" - WSCF Africa Region (112 pp), ca. 2012 (Box 6, Folder 12)